<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spice on Aromatica</title>
    <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/categories/spice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spice on Aromatica</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/categories/spice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Allspice</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/allspice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/allspice/</guid>
      <description>Allspice (Pimenta dioica (L.) Merr.) is a culinary spice from the Myrtaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of S. Mexico to C. America; Caribbean.2 It is used for its unripe fruit and leaf, primarily for pickles, wines, desserts, liquors. Its aroma is described as pungent, mixed, spicy, with a heat index of 4.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese szegfűbors فلفل إفرنجي 多香果 Overview id allspice species name Pimenta dioica (L.) Merr. family Myrtaceae part used unripe fruit; leaf macroarea Americas region of origin S.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anise</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/anise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/anise/</guid>
      <description>Anise (Pimpinella anisum L.) is a culinary spice from the Apiaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of nan.2 It is used for its fruit and oil, primarily for pastries, candies, liquors. Its aroma is described as licorice-like, sweet, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese ánizs أنيسون 茴芹 Overview id anise species name Pimpinella anisum L. family Apiaceae part used fruit; oil macroarea Med.; W. Asia region of origin nan cultivation Turkey; Egypt; Spain; Russia; Italy; etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asafoetida</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/asafoetida/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/asafoetida/</guid>
      <description>Asafoetida (Ferula foetida (Bunge) Regel) is a culinary and medicinal spice from the Apiaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Iran; W. and C. Asia.2 It is used for its gum-resin (latex), primarily for curries; expectorant. Its aroma is described as pungent, rotten, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese ördöggyökér حلتیت 阿魏 Overview id asafoetida species name Ferula foetida (Bunge) Regel family Apiaceae part used gum-resin (latex) macroarea Asia region of origin Iran; W.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caraway</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/caraway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/caraway/</guid>
      <description>Caraway (Carum carvi L.) is a culinary spice from the Apiaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Mediterranean; Eurasia.2 It is used for its fruit, primarily for breads, sausages, cheese; carminative. Its aroma is described as warm, sweet, anise-like, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese fűszerkömény كراويا 葛縷子 Overview id caraway species name Carum carvi L. family Apiaceae part used fruit macroarea Eurasia region of origin Mediterranean; Eurasia cultivation Denmark; Lebanon; The Netherlands; Poland color dark brown botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cardamom</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/cardamom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/cardamom/</guid>
      <description>Cardamom (Elettaria cardamomum (L.) Maton) is a culinary spice from the Zingiberaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of India.2 It is used for its fruit (seed pods, capsules), primarily for desserts, coffees, curries. Its aroma is described as pungent, eucalyptus-like, with a heat index of 2.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese kardamom هال 豆蔻 Overview id cardamom species name Elettaria cardamomum (L.) Maton family Zingiberaceae part used fruit (seed pods, capsules) macroarea Asia region of origin India cultivation Guatemala; India; Sri Lanka; Tanzania; Papua New Guinea color green seed pods, brown seeds botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cassia</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/cassia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/cassia/</guid>
      <description>Cassia (Cinnamomum cassia (L.) J.Presl.) is a culinary and medicinal spice from the Lauraceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of nan.2 It is used for its bark and fruit, primarily for flavor; diarrhea. Its aroma is described as pungent, cinnamon-like, with a heat index of 3.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese kasszia(fahéj) سليخة 肉桂 Overview id cassia species name Cinnamomum cassia (L.) J.Presl. family Lauraceae part used bark; fruit macroarea Asia region of origin nan cultivation Indonesia; China; Vietnam; Timor-Leste; etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chile</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/chile/</guid>
      <description>Chile (Capsicum annuum L.) is a culinary spice from the Solanaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Central America.2 It is used for its fruit, primarily for flavors; analgesic. Its aroma is described as pungent, fiery, with a heat index of 4-10.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese paprika فلفل حار 辣椒 Overview id chile species name Capsicum annuum L. family Solanaceae part used fruit macroarea Americas region of origin Central America cultivation Ethiopia; India; Kenya; Mexico; Nigeria; Pakistan; Tanzania; etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cinnamon</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/cinnamon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/cinnamon/</guid>
      <description>Cinnamon (Cinnamomum verum J.Presl.) is a culinary and medicinal spice from the Lauraceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Sri Lanka; SW. India.2 It is used for its bark and leaf, primarily for flavor; anti-microbial. Its aroma is described as sweet, fragrant, pungent, with a heat index of 3.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese fahéj قرفة 錫蘭肉桂 Overview id cinnamon species name Cinnamomum verum J.Presl. family Lauraceae part used bark; leaf macroarea Asia region of origin Sri Lanka; SW.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clove</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/clove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/clove/</guid>
      <description>Clove (Syzygium aromaticum (L.) Merr. &amp;amp; L.M.Perry) is a culinary and medicinal spice from the Myrtaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Moluccas (Indonesia).2 It is used for its flower buds, primarily for meats, sauces; anesthetic. Its aroma is described as sweet, pungent, astringent, with a heat index of 5.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese szegfűszeg قرنفل 丁香 Overview id clove species name Syzygium aromaticum (L.) Merr. &amp;amp; L.M.Perry family Myrtaceae part used flower buds macroarea Asia region of origin Moluccas (Indonesia) cultivation Indonesia; Malaysia; Tanzania color rich, reddish brown botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coriander</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/coriander/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/coriander/</guid>
      <description>Coriander (Coriandrum sativum L.) is a culinary spice and herb from the Apiaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Mediterranean; W. Asia; India; SW As.2 It is used for its fruit and leaf, primarily for curries; anti-microbial. Its aroma is described as warm, aromatic, sweet, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese koriander كزبرة 芫荽 Overview id coriander species name Coriandrum sativum L. family Apiaceae part used fruit; leaf macroarea Asia region of origin Mediterranean; W.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cumin</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/cumin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/cumin/</guid>
      <description>Cumin (Cuminum cyminum L.) is a culinary spice from the Apiaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of W. &amp;amp; C. Asia; India .2 It is used for its fruit, primarily for curries, breads; colic. Its aroma is described as peppery, aromatic, with a heat index of 4.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese római kömény كمون 孜然 Overview id cumin species name Cuminum cyminum L. family Apiaceae part used fruit macroarea Asia region of origin W.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dill</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/dill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/dill/</guid>
      <description>Dill (Anethum graveolens L.) is a culinary spice and herb from the Apiaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Nort Africa; West Asia.2 It is used for its fruit and leaf, primarily for pickles, fish, breads; gripe. Its aroma is described as bitter-sweet, cool, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese kapor شبت 蒔蘿 Overview id dill species name Anethum graveolens L. family Apiaceae part used fruit; leaf macroarea Med.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fennel</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/fennel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/fennel/</guid>
      <description>Fennel (Foeniculum vulgare Mill.) is a culinary spice and herb and vegetable from the Apiaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Med.2 It is used for its fruit and leaf, primarily for fish, breads, sausages; colic. Its aroma is described as licorice-like, warm, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese édeskömény شمر 茴香 Overview id fennel species name Foeniculum vulgare Mill. family Apiaceae part used fruit; leaf macroarea Med.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fenugreek</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/fenugreek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/fenugreek/</guid>
      <description>Fenugreek (Trigonella foenum-graecum L.) is a culinary spice and herb from the Fabaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of S Eur; W As.2 It is used for its seed and leaf, primarily for curries, breads; diabetes. Its aroma is described as like burnt sugar, bitter, with a heat index of 2.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese görögszéna حلبة 胡蘆巴 Overview id fenugreek species name Trigonella foenum-graecum L. family Fabaceae part used seed; leaf macroarea Asia region of origin S Eur; W As cultivation India color yellow seeds botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ginger</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/ginger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/ginger/</guid>
      <description>Ginger (Zingiber officinale Roscoe) is a culinary and medicinal spice from the Zingiberaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of South East Asia; India (secondary).2 It is used for its rhizome, primarily for Asian cooking; anti-emetic. Its aroma is described as fiery, pungent, with a heat index of 7.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese gyömbér زنجبيل 薑 Overview id ginger species name Zingiber officinale Roscoe family Zingiberaceae part used rhizome macroarea Asia region of origin South East Asia; India (secondary) cultivation India; Jamaica; Nigeria; Sierra Leone color light yellow when fresh, beige when powdered botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Pepper</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/long_pepper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/long_pepper/</guid>
      <description>Long Pepper (Piper longum L.) is a culinary and medicinal spice from the Piperaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of E. Himalaya to S. China; Indo-China.2 It is used for its fruit, primarily for South and Souteast Asian cuisine; Ayurveda and TCM. Its aroma is described as pungent, peppery, with a heat index of 4-9.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese hosszú bors دارفلفل 蓽撥 Overview id long pepper species name Piper longum L.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mace</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/mace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/mace/</guid>
      <description>Mace (Myristica fragrans Houtt.) is a culinary spice from the Myristicaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Moluccas (Indonesia).2 It is used for its aril, primarily for confectionary; peptic ulcers. Its aroma is described as sweet, bitter, salty, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese szerecsendió-virág بسباسة 肉豆蔻皮 Overview id mace species name Myristica fragrans Houtt. family Myristicaceae part used aril macroarea Asia region of origin Moluccas (Indonesia) cultivation Grenada; Indonesia color crimson red aril whn fresh, pale yellow when dried botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nutmeg</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/nutmeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/nutmeg/</guid>
      <description>Nutmeg (Myristica fragrans Houtt.) is a culinary spice from the Myristicaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Moluccas (Indonesia).2 It is used for its seed, primarily for desserts, eggnog; diahrrhea. Its aroma is described as sweet, warm, nutty, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese szerecsendió جوز الطيب 肉豆蔻 Overview id nutmeg species name Myristica fragrans Houtt. family Myristicaceae part used seed macroarea Asia region of origin Moluccas (Indonesia) cultivation Grenada; Indonesia color pale brown nut, dark when powdered botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pepper</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/pepper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/pepper/</guid>
      <description>Pepper (Piper nigrum L.) is a culinary and medicinal spice from the Piperaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Malabar coast (South India).2 It is used for its fruit, primarily for flavors; colds. Its aroma is described as pungent, hot, with a heat index of 3-8.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese bors فلفل 胡椒 Overview id pepper species name Piper nigrum L. family Piperaceae part used fruit macroarea Asia region of origin Malabar coast (South India) cultivation Vietnam; Brazil; Indonesia; India; Sri Lanka; etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saffron</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/saffron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/saffron/</guid>
      <description>Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) is a culinary spice and dye from the Iridaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Greece.2 It is used for its stigma (style), primarily for bouillabaise, rice; fevers. Its aroma is described as pungent, bitter, with a heat index of 0.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese sáfrány زعفران 藏紅花 Overview id saffron species name Crocus sativus L. family Iridaceae part used stigma (style) macroarea Mediterranean region of origin Greece cultivation Iran; Spain; Kashmir; etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sichuan Pepper</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/sichuan_pepper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/sichuan_pepper/</guid>
      <description>Sichuan Pepper (Zanthoxylum bungeanum Maxim.) is a culinary spice from the Rutaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of China.2 It is used for its pericarp, primarily for meats; colic. Its aroma is described as woodsy, peppery, with a heat index of 3.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese szecsuáni bors فلفل سيتشوان 花椒 Overview id Sichuan pepper species name Zanthoxylum bungeanum Maxim. family Rutaceae part used pericarp macroarea Asia region of origin China cultivation China color red; green botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Anise</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/star_anise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/star_anise/</guid>
      <description>Star Anise (Illicium verum Hook.f.) is a culinary spice from the Schisandraceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of SE. China; Vietnam.2 It is used for its pericarp, primarily for meats, desserts; colic. Its aroma is described as bitter, licorice-like, with a heat index of 3.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese csillagánizs يانسون نجمي 八角 Overview id star anise species name Illicium verum Hook.f. family Schisandraceae part used pericarp macroarea Asia region of origin SE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turmeric</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/turmeric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/turmeric/</guid>
      <description>Turmeric (Curcuma longa L.) is a culinary and medicinal and ritualistic spice and dye from the Zingiberaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of India.2 It is used for its rhizome, primarily for curries, dye; antiseptic. Its aroma is described as warm, acrid, bitter, with a heat index of 3.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese kurkuma كركم 薑黃 Overview id turmeric species name Curcuma longa L. family Zingiberaceae part used rhizome macroarea Asia region of origin India cultivation China; Honduras; India; Indonesia; Jamaica color orange-yellow botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/vanilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/materials/vanilla/</guid>
      <description>Vanilla (Vanilla planifolia Jacks. ex Andrews) is a culinary spice from the Orchidaceae family,1 originating in the region(s) of Tropical America.2 It is used for its fruit, primarily for flavouring; baking; desserts; perfumery; aromatherapy. Its aroma is described as fragrant, sweet, delicious, with a heat index of 1.3
Hungarian Arabic Chinese vanília فانيليا 香草 Overview id vanilla species name Vanilla planifolia Jacks. ex Andrews family Orchidaceae part used fruit macroarea Americas region of origin Tropical America cultivation Madagascar; Indonesia; Mexico; Papua New Guinea; China color dark brown pod; creamy white extract botanical database POWO POWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/testing/</guid>
      <description>Lorem Ipsum.
Box
There may be pirates It is all about the boxes.
Badge
Version6.6.6 Button
Get Hugo Expand me&amp;hellip; Thank you! CodeIcons
pie title Spice names by language&amp;#34;English&amp;#34; : 120&amp;#34;Arabic&amp;#34; : 90&amp;#34;Chinese&amp;#34; : 60Plotly</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sources</title>
      <link>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://partigabor.github.io/aromatica/sources/</guid>
      <description>In what follows, you can find the main resources that were used while creating the database, and the rationale behind the selection. The first step was to try and assemble a list of spices that are relatively well-known, using materials and information gathered by professionals from various fields. The second step was to collate information on these materials, standardize our &amp;ldquo;master list&amp;rdquo;, and conduct research on each. Along the way, new and less common materials would reveal themselves, and their addition would help the ultimate goal of an exhaustive, comprehensive list of spices.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>